Guide to the Bruce Voeller papers, 1956-1990
Voeller, Bruce papers, 1956-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bruce Voeller papers, 1956-1990
7307
Bruce R. Voeller
45 cubic feet
Subject files, clippings, leaflets, flyers, broadsides, newsletters, periodicals, mailings, typescript.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Materials pertaining to sexuality in general and to homosexuality and the gay liberation movement in particular; includes subject files on AIDS and sexually transmitted diseases. Also a typescript of a prose fiction by Voeller, "Murder at McGurk." Files pertaining to the Responsive Gay Collective, the Gay Media Alliance, demonstrations in New York City, the Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, the 1979 Gay Pride Celebration in New York City, the Lesbian and Gay Neighbors of Lower Manhattan, and the Chelsea Gay Association.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
A biologist, researcher, and founder of the Mariposa Education and Research Foundation, Voeller died from AIDS-related complications on February 13, 1994 at his home in Topanga, Calif. Voeller was perhaps best known for coining the acronym AIDS for "acquired immune deficiency syndrome," a term he used in objection to the disease's earlier label, GRID, or "gay-related immune disorder." From 1961 to 1972, he held various positions on the faculty of Rockefeller University. A prominent gay rights activist, Voeller helped found the National Gay Task Force (NGTF) in 1973 and with Jean O'Leary, served as first co-directors. He also served as President of the Gay Activists Alliance in New York City. In 1980, Voeller established the Mariposa Foundation based in Topanga, to conduct human sexuality research, placing special emphasis on reducing the risks of sexually transmitted diseases. At the time of his death, Voeller's research with the Mariposa Foundation centered on the reliability of various brands of condoms in preventing the spread of diseases. A result of this research was a study funded in part by the American Foundation for AIDS Research and the National Institutes of Health, that ranked 31 brands of condoms under various conditions. Voeller was also conducting viral leakage studies for the recently approved "female" condom.
Mariposa also worked to protect research material on the social and political aspects of sexuality. Aware that papers, books, and ephemera on the lesbian and gay rights movement were in particular danger of being lost or destroyed, a network of volunteers searched for and gathered such material together. As this collection grew, Voeller and his friend David B. Goodstein began to consider how to ensure its preservation and professional care, make it more widely accessible for scholarship, and increase its visibility. They believed that the time had come for a major research library to take up the project of documenting sexuality. The gift of the Mariposa archives to Cornell University Library in 1988 launched such a program -- the Human Sexuality Collection.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Bruce Voeller collection consists of correspondence, reprints and photocopies of reports, periodicals, and the practical and perfunctory unsolicited mailings of information by a large number of organizations, associations, and gay special interest groups, all of which concern themselves with gay and lesbian issues of health care, activism and politics, public awareness, celebration, and fundraising. These mailings display the varied statements of information and notification, invitations, and assertions of need and concern in gay and lesbian society, from the liberation and matters of entitlement and empowerment, to its recognition of and dealing with AIDS, both politically and medically. Several hundred American gay and lesbian organizations and groups are represented in the collection. Voeller's role in the transfer of the Mariposa Education and Research Foundation's Archives to Cornell University, and the establishment of David B. Goodstein's bequest is documented in the correspondence. Also included is the typescript of prose fiction by Voeller, "Murder at McGurk."
Also, files pertaining to the Responsive Gay Collective, the Gay Media Alliance, demonstrations in New York City, the Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, the 1979 Gay Pride Celebration in New York City, the Lesbian and Gay Neighbors of Lower Manhattan, and the Chelsea Gay Association.
Also, photographs of Voeller with other gay activists and sexuality researchers including Evelyn Hooker, staff of the National Gay Task Force, David McWhirter, Andrew Mattison, and Jean O'Leary; Voeller's research files on condoms and the prevention of sexually transmitted diseases; Voeller's articles on topics of botany, sexually transmitted diseases, and gay fathers and gay rights; and Voeller's files from the gay rights movement and his work with the Mariposa Foundation, 1973-1990.
Files on botany include a small collection of dried plant specimens.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Voeller, Bruce R.; Responsive Gay Collective.; Gay Media Alliance.; Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee.; Lesbian and Gay Neighbors of Lower Manhattan.; Chelsea Gay Association (New York, N.Y.).; Mariposa Foundation.; National Gay Task Force.
Subjects:
Homosexuality.; AIDS (Disease).; Gay men.; Lesbians.; Gay liberation movement.; Gays.; Sexually transmitted diseases--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Materials were accumulated from several sources.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Materials are arranged according to the original folder headings, when present, which are the primary level of access.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Subject Files and Correspondence
General Subject And Correspondence Files
Boxes 1-11, 32-41,
53, 55-57, 63
AIDS
Boxes 12-19
Venereal Disease
Boxes 19-20
Anal Sex
Boxes 20-21
Semen
Box 21
AIDS Conferences
Boxes 21-22, 63
Condoms
Box 22
AIDS Miscellaneous
Boxes 22-23
Spermicides
Box 23
Kinsey Files
Boxes 30-31
AIDS Research and Public Policy Reports
Box 31
AIDS Barrier Contraception Investigation
Boxes 42-49
Series II. Early Scientific Research
Boxes 52, 54, 58-60, 62-65
Series III. Recordings
Box 61
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Subject Files and Correspondence
  - General Subject And Correspondence Files
    - Mariposa Collection at Cornell, 1984-1986; Correspondence with David R. Dunlop and the Office of University Development; also correspondence with David B. Goodstein, Louis E. Martin, Arthur Leonard, and others (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
    - Clippings pertaining to the Acquisition of the Mariposa Collection by Cornell University, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence and Printed Material, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
    - Advice Columnists (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Advocate Experience (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Art/Artists (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Body Politic Trial, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Briggs/Briggs Initiative (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Anita Bryant (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Businesses/NABC (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - CBS TV, "Gay Power, Gay Politics", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Chelsea Gay Association, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Church Lobbying (Anti-Gay), 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - CLONE: Reference/Resources for Future Issues (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Rights (CLGR), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Rights (CLGR), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Cruising" (film), 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - Damien, John, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Dan White Verdict, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Discrimination, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Discrimination Investigations, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 1977 Elections, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Elections 1980/Gay Vote 1980, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - FBI (Gay Investigations), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - FCC (Federal Communications Commission), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Films/Film-makers (Gay), 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Jimmy Flowers (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Foreign Countries, Gay (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Gay Activists Alliance (GAA), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Gay Atheists League of America, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Gay Academic Union (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "Gay Community News" (in house), 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Gay Anarchists, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Gay Leaflets (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Gay Media Alliance, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Gay Movement: Straight Press, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Gay Rights Bill - New York City (Box 1, Folder 50-51)
    - Gay Teachers in the Classroom, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - General Anti-Gay Articles (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Glines, 1980; "a not-for-profit organization dedicated to the creation, production and promotion of art which represents the many aspects of the gay experience." (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Greyhound (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Heterosexuality (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Gay History, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - John Paul Hudson (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Hustling (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Immigration, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - International Lesbian and Gay Association, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Intro 2 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Jesus March/Washington for Jesus, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Judicial (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Bob Kunst/C.U.R.E. (Congress United for Rights and Equality), 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Liberation Movement Theory (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Lobbying (Procedures, Forms, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - March on Washington, Oct. 14, 1979, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - March on Albany, April 12, 1980, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Bruce Voeller's resume (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Matlovich, Leonard (Tech Sergeant, U.S. Air Force), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Media Groups - Action (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Miami (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Music (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - National Gay Task Force - Fund for Human Dignity, 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5-12)
    - National Gay Task Force, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13-24)
    - MECLA - Municipal Elections Committee of Los Angeles, Invitations (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - MECLA (cont.), 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - GLID - Gay and Lesbian Independent Democrats, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
    - Miscellaneous Gay and Lesbian Mailings and Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "Political Reports", 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
    - Miscellaneous Political Mailings, Press Releases, 1981-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33-38)
    - Gay Rights National Lobby (GRNL), 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 39-43)
    - Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders (GLAD), 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - National Gay Rights Advocate (NGRA), 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - International Lesbian/Gay Freedom Day, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Gay Pride Festival, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Gay Pride Festival (cont.), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous Activism Mailings (Causes, Rallies, Marches), 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 48-55)
    - Senior Action in a Gay Environment (SAGE), 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    - The Center (Los Angeles Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center), 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7-9)
    - The Center (cont.), 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10-13)
    - Greater Gotham Business Council, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
    - Human Rights Campaign Fund, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Mailings of Organizations of Parents of Gays and Lesbians, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 18-22)
    - Miscellaneous Mailings of Organizations re: Religion and Gays, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 23-27)
    - "One Letter" "One Calendar", 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
    - Racial/Sexual, 1981-1987; Including publications of Men of All Colors Together/Black and White Men Together, Los Angeles Black and White Men Together (Box 3, Folder 30-36)
    - "Paz Y Liberacion", 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous International Gay Publications and Organizations, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Science and Health Issues, 1981-1988; Publications and periodicals of the Triangle Area Gay Scientists, the Pride Institute (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Education, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "Gay Ol' Times", 1983-1990 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Michigan Organization for Human Rights (MOHR), c. 1987 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - The Coalition Together, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous Lesbian/Women's Publications, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 45-47)
    - College and University Gay and Lesbian Organizations and Publications, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "This Is It" - A Bi-Monthly Newsletter Published by the Advocate Research and Education Fund, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - "GVA Newsletter" (Gay Veterans Association), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 51-56)
    - Legal Cases, Briefs, and Transcripts of Gay Judicial Actions, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 57-64)
    - Press Releases, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 65-67)
    - Broadsides, c. 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 68-69)
    - New York City, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Miscellaneous Broadsides, Press Releases, and FYIs, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 71-72)
    - Brochures, Booklets, Notices of Information, c. 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Invitations and Announcements, c. 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
    - Mail Order Catalogs, c. 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 7-12)
    - Miscellaneous Mailings, c. 1981-1990; Including several of the above categories, forms, and topics (Box 4, Folder 13-41)
    - Miscellaneous Mailings, c. 1981-1990; Including several of the above categories, forms, and topics (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - "Village Voice", 1980 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bank of Los Angeles, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Gaysweek" (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Report of the Pennsylvania Council for Sexual Minorities, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - St. Paul Post Election Survey (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Published Articles on Homosexuality and Sexual Deviance, 1950-1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "American Psychologist", 1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Report - Sexual Exploitation of Children, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - MMPI (Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory) Notebook, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Reports, 1976-1989 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
    - "Lavender Network", 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - New York City "Pride Guide", 1983 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Gay Music Performances, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - GMHC (Gay Men's Health Crisis) AIDS Benefit Program, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Project Open Understanding, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Brochures, Directories, Reports and Mailings, c. 1981-1989 (Box 5, Folder 24-38)
    - Manuscripts, Reprints, Photocopies, c. 1980-1990 (Box 5, Folder 39-50)
    - AIDS Reports and Articles, 1982-1984; Includes correspondence with Great Lakes Products (Box 6, Folder 1-12)
    - AIDS Reports and Articles, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 13-19)
    - Centers for Disease control "Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report", 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
    - Articles About AIDS in Foreign and Domestic Magazines, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 22-28)
    - AIDS File; Miscellaneous Press Clippings, Photocopies of Reports, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, c. 1980-1990 (Box 6, Folder 29-54)
    - 412 page Typescript: "Murder at McGurk" (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 8)
    - "Cruising" Gay Media Alliance Part 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Bars Distribution (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Gay Media Alliance Part 2, 1979-83, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
    - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee Media, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous - mailings from gay and lesbian organizations; campaign against the movie "Cruising", 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence Out, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Legal/Police Information, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Purchase Receipts (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Documentary Film, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Gay Media Alliance, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Paid Receipts C.A.T.M.C., 1979 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sexual Minorities (Box 9, Folder 14-17)
    - Clippings, 1977-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
    - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Supporting documents: Notices and advertisements, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Supporting documents: Notices and advertisements, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Supporting documents: Notices and advertisements, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Supporting documents: Notices and advertisements, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Supporting documents: Notices and advertisements, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - Supporting documents: Notices and advertisements, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Supporting documents: Notices and advertisements (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Cruising (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Board packet, January 16-17, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, Includes Bruce Voeller medical history, information on sexually transmitted diseases, personal correspondence (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Mail - Mariposa (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Foreign-clippings, publications, letters (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Photographs (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "Library Legal Reference Guild Press Archive" (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Supporting documents: newsletters (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Lesbian and gay announcements, flyers (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Supporting documents: mailings (Box 10, Folder 24-30)
    - Draft of Mariposa Education and Research Foundation pamphlet (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Chvapil, M. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Connell, E.B. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Cuttler (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
    - Gonorrhea (Box 11, Folder 5-8)
    - Iodine (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Jick, H. (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
    - Lazar (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Levy, Jay (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Liao, Winston (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Limsuwan, A. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Mahoney (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "A" Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Advocate Research and Education Fund (AREF) (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Abortion (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Advertisements (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Advocate (Box 32, Folder 5-7)
    - Advocate Experience (Box 32, Folder 8-12)
    - Advocate Experience Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Advocate Experience Promotion (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Alexander (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - American Foundation for the Prevention of Venereal Disease (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Amoebae and Giardia (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Anal Sex - H Anorectal Cancer (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Anal Sex - Oleogranulomas (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Anal Sex - Oils (Box 32, Folder 20-21)
    - Anderson - 06-16 Citations (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Anderson - Reprints (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Anthony, Michael (Box 32, Folder 24-25)
    - Apuzzo, Ginny (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Art Auction (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - AVATAR (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - "B" Correspondence (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Bay Area Physicians for Human Rights (BAPHR) (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Baths (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Behar, Mark (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Benefits (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Bequests (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Berg, Stan (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Berger, B. S. (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Bibliographies (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Bio-Techniques Labs (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Bisexuality (Box 32, Folder 39-40)
    - Black and White Men Together (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Bolan, Dr. Robert (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Bolling, Dave (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Brandt, Edward (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Brown Memorial Clinic, Howard (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
    - Buc, Nancy (Box 33, Folder 6-8)
    - Buchanon Project (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Bush, Larry (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Bush Report (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - "C" Correspondence (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - CDC (Center for Disease Control) - Wiesner (Paul J. Weisner, M.D., Director, Venereal Disease Control Division) (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - CDC (Center for Disease Control) - Venereal Disease Statistics (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Cytomegalovirus (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Cameron Iron Works (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Cameron, Paul (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Chancroid (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Chapel Hill Fertility Sues (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Chicago Resource Center (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Children (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Chlamydia (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Christmas Gifts (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Circumcision (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Clergy (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Cline, Steve (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Colt Studios (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Comegys, Duke (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Competitors (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Complaint Letters (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Conant (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Condyloma (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Contraception (Box 33, Folder 33)
      - Contraceptive Choice (Box 33, Folder 34)
      - Contraceptive Efficacy (Box 33, Folder 35)
      - Hazards (Box 33, Folder 36)
      - Injectable contraception (Box 33, Folder 37)
      - IUDs (Box 33, Folder 38)
      - Prevention - Governmental (Box 33, Folder 39)
      - Pill (Box 33, Folder 40)
      - Vaginal (Box 33, Folder 40a)
    - Cornell (Box 33, Folder 41-43)
      - Expense Reimbursement (Box 33, Folder 44)
      - Mariposa Contract (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - Consumer's Union (Box 33, Folder 46)
    - Constanza, Midge (Box 33, Folder 47)
    - Cranks (Box 33, Folder 48)
    - Curran (Box 33, Folder 49)
    - Cutler (Box 33, Folder 50)
    - Cornell: Expense; Contraceptives; Cling, Steve; Cytomegalovirus (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - "D" Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - DeCrow, Karen (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Decker, Bruce (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Determinants (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Deukmejian, Gov. George (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Direct Mail (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Direct Mail - Ron Spyrison (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - DeBlase, Tony Dungeon Master (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Dorner (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - "E" Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - EBV - Epstein Barr Virus (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Ellis (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Endowments, Trust (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - English, Ron (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Enlow, Roger (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Envelopes (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - "F" Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 17-18)
    - FBI and CIA "Spooks" (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Family Health International (FHI) (Box 34, Folder 20-22)
    - FHI - NIH Application for GC/Chlamydia Trials (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - FHI (Box 34, Folder 24-26)
    - FHI - Eli Carter (Box 34, Folder 27-28)
    - Fain, Nathan (Box 34, Folder 29)
    - Falk, Larry (Box 34, Folder 30)
    - Falwell, Jerry (Box 34, Folder 31)
    - Famous Gays (Box 34, Folder 32)
    - Family Planning Demographics (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - Federal Register (Box 34, Folder 34)
    - Findley Research (Box 34, Folder 35)
    - Finn, Martin D. (Box 34, Folder 36)
    - Firemen (Box 34, Folder 37)
    - Flashbacks (Box 34, Folder 38)
    - Forum Magazine (Box 34, Folder 39)
    - Foster (Box 34, Folder 40)
    - Foundations (Box 34, Folder 41-42)
    - Goodstein, David (Box 34, Folder 43-44)
    - Goodstein, Edward (Box 34, Folder 45)
    - Grant Seeker Guide (Box 34, Folder 46)
    - Guarantees/Warranties (Box 34, Folder 47)
    - Foundations (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
      - New York Community Trust (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Skaggs (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Windom Fund (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Fund - Human Dignity (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Fund Raising (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Fund - Human Dignity (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Further Action (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - "G" Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 10)